What do we mean? When we say threats and vulnerabilities,
a
vulnerability is a gap or weakness in
an organization's protection of its valuable assets,
including information,
a
threat is something or someone that aims
to exploit a vulnerability to gain unauthorized access
by exploiting a vulnerability. The threat can harm an asset,
for example,
a natural disaster such as a major storm poses a
threat to the utility power supply which is vulnerable to flooding
the it environment where production takes place is an asset.
If the utility power supply is cut off by a storm,
the asset might be made unavailable because
the it components won't work without power.
Our job is to evaluate how likely it is that an event
will take place and take appropriate actions to mitigate the risk.